three things I like about the gym
Reaper's 10 millimeter lever weight
lifting belt or the fully leather build
the buckles actually adjustable and the
lever is going to make sure the belt
does not come undone while you're
working out now not everybody uses a
belt when they lift but I personally
think the right one can be huge for
those days when you're maxing out I've
been getting after it with this belt for
a while so let's go ahead and break
everything down for y'all
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review ready to go for y'all this time
I've got the gym Reapers 10 millimeter
lever weight lifting belt so I figured
I'd go ahead and put on my Grim Reaper
shirt for you guys in this video I'm
going to tell you everything you need to
know about this belt and the price and
the features of course some pros and
cons and who should or maybe should not
throw this in their gym bag but one more
thing before I get going today you know
we've reviewed a ton of weightlifting
belts on barbin.com so if you want to
browse our best list just go and search
barvin best weightlifting belts and you
can find out for yourself which one
cracks the number one spot
foreign
[Music]
a little bit on what I like about this
weightlifting Bill well first and
foremost support matters when you're
lifting heavy weight and when I'm doing
some heavy squats I definitely feel
supported with this belt because of the
fully leather build and that 10
millimeter thickness the Buckle right
here is really cool in my opinion how
there's multiple adjustments you can use
so that way you know you always are
going to be able to find that sweet spot
and make it perfectly nice and tight
against your body you know give your
core something to brace against and also
you know this lever right here it's got
two little hooks two little teeth I
guess you could say so they're going to
hook in over here on this other side and
really don't think you're gonna have any
problem whatsoever with this belt
staying locked into place on you while
you're working out
[Music]
foreign
okay so let's talk about a few cons I
could see with this belt first of all
it's kind of expensive Priced Right
Around 120 dollars which is honestly
pretty average compared to the rest of
the market but you know that's still a
lot of money you'll be spending on just
a weightlifting bill because it is in
fact fully leather it's going to be more
stiff than let's say a nylon belt would
be so I think this is going to be more
suited for power lifting so if you're an
Olympic lifter or a crossfitter probably
want to check out a fully nylon belt Jim
Reapers has a good one but you know
that's not really what this is intended
for and lastly you know leather belts in
general can be a little bit more
constricting on you when you're lifting
and it might make it a little bit
difficult to breathe at certain times
[Music]
okay so in terms of pricing you know
once again the gym Reaper's 10
millimeter lever weightlifting belt is
listed right around 120 bucks you can
purchase this directly from the Jim
Reaper's website or you know you could
even get it on Amazon if you'd rather do
that now be honest you know once again
120 bucks for a weightlifting belt you
know pretty penny to say the least but
compared to the rest of the market you
know it's actually pretty average and
there's some out there that are a little
bit more expensive than this belt is and
you know once you really factor in the
fact that you know you're going to get
pretty much the best support you can ask
for and this Buckle is technically
customizable since you can adjust it
really however you please I think this
is a pretty solid deal
foreign
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
with this weightlifting belt you know
once again this is made of 100 leather
it's got the 10 millimeter thickness and
you have this matte black steel buckle
you pair all that together and you're
really going to get the best support
that you can you can ask for now we have
the black one but there's eight
different colors for you to choose from
and it's available in six different
sizes so there really is a solid chance
that you're gonna be able to find that
exact one for you
foreign
[Applause]
okay so let's expand a little bit with
this weight lifting belt it features a
four inch wide profile and it's not
tapered in the front which the tapered
belt can be helpful when you're doing a
deadlift for example when you're leaning
over to grab the barbell you know I
haven't really experienced any type of
an issue with this belt but I definitely
understand why some people
could experience an issue you do have a
lever right here on the front and it's
got two little teeth that are gonna you
know fit nicely in these grooves on the
other end of the belt and I really don't
think you're gonna have any problem
whatsoever with this belt staying nice
and tight against your body comes in six
different sizes ranging from extra small
all the way up to double XL and whenever
you go to you know measure yourself for
your specific belt you want to measure
around your belly button because that's
where the belt is going to be now
whenever you measure yourself make sure
you head over to their website it has
everything detailed on what size is
going to be for what measurement
all right y'all let's go and do a quick
walk around with this 10 millimeter
lever weight lifting belt so once again
this is made of 100 leather you do have
suede on the front and the back just to
make it more comfortable but I really
like how this is you know full leather
it's going to give you that optimal
support you know when you're lifting
heavy your Buckle is made of steel and
you have two little teeth right here
that's going to be huge in terms of you
know keeping this Buckle locked into
place and keeping the belt from coming
undone on you now when you first get
your belt this Buckle is not going to be
fastened in there so what you do is
you'll you know pick the spot where you
need yours to go screw everything in
together that's pretty much all there is
to it now
when you put it on it's really simple
just make sure everything lines up put
these two little teeth in the little
slot right there
just give it a nice press down and then
it's it's super I have mine pretty tight
right now it's how I like lifting you
can always you know adjust it and make
it a little looser even tighter if you
want to but this is really going to give
you that optimal support when you're
doing some heavy squats you know once
again it's available in six different
sizes from extra small all the way up to
double XL it also comes in eight
different colors as well
foreign
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the Jim
Reaper's 10 millimeter lever weight
lifting belt well anybody who wants the
maximum support that's provided from a
thicker fully leather belt like this one
right here you know I think you're
really gonna like the 10 millimeter
thickness that you have here and plus
this lever right here and the Buckle you
know it's going to make sure it doesn't
come undone on you while you're lifting
and that's obviously something you don't
want to happen and any athlete who's
competing in powerlifting competitions
and you know you're in the market for a
USPA approved weightlifting belt I think
this is a really solid choice that you
should consider
foreign
[Music]
okay so who should not purchase this
belt well really it just boils down to
your workout preference so if you're
somebody who's focusing on a lot of
Olympic and Crossfit style lifts you're
probably not going to want to snag this
belt right here because it's definitely
more stiff than what a 100 nylon belt
would be maybe even a hybrid belt would
be so that's definitely something to
consider and you might want to check out
some other options and then if you don't
if you aren't too crazy about the
adjustment mechanism right here I'd
suggest you know checking out some belts
that feature a velcro strap
foreign
[Music]
that's about all I have for you guys
today on the gym Reaper's 10 millimeter
lever weight lifting belt I personally
love lifting heavy with this belt since
it provides my core with the exact
support that I need you know for those
heavy squats for example it is kind of
expensive you know 120 bucks or so but
that's pretty average and the fact that
it's made of full leather and you have
your steel Buckle right here it's pretty
much guaranteed to last you a lifetime
thanks for watching y'all I hope this
video was really helpful and I was able
to answer any questions you may have
about this weightlifting belt as always
stay tuned for my next video but for now
head over to barbin.com and you can read
more about this product just search bar
Bend Jim Reaper's 10 millimeter lever
weightlifting belt review and you'll
find everything that I talked about here
today I'll see y'all next time
foreign
[Music]